Finding Aid for University Unions Graphic Design Office (University of Michigan) Student Work, 1984-2011
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
University Unions Graphic Design Office (University of Michigan) Student Work 1984-2011
University of Michigan. University Unions. Graphic Design Office.
3.71 GB of digital files
35 oversize volumes
2010124 Bimu F15 2
Graphic design office staffed by junior and senior students majoring in graphic design and screen arts & cultures, serving the three University of Michigan student unions (Michigan League, Michigan Union, Pierpont Commons). Collection consists of chronologically arranged scrapbooks and digital files containing designs and work samples including brochures, fliers, forms, signs, and advertising for campus offices, organizations and events.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Received from the University Unions Graphic Design Office (Donor no. 10349 ) in June 2010 and October 2011.
Periodic additions to the collections are expected.
The collection is open without restriction.
University Unions Graphic Design Office (UUGDO) is a branch of the University Unions, an organizational unit within the Division of Student Affairs that offers services, programs, spaces and student involvement opportunities within the Michigan League, Michigan Union, and Pierpont Commons.
Originally named the Graphic Design Shop upon its establishment in 1985, UUGDO provides graphic design services for units in the University of Michigan's Office of Student Affair. UUGDO offers consultations on publicity budgets and organizational branding in as well as design and production in various media and genres, including booklets, logos, brochures, posters, direct mail pieces, t-shirts, signs, forms, newspaper ads, and imprinted advertising novelties. The design staff is comprised of juniors and seniors majoring in graphic design at the University of Michigan School of Art & Design and includes internship opportunities. Undergraduate students from the Screen Arts & Cultures department are also on staff and lead the production of promotional videos. The design internships teach the day-to-day skills of the profession: dealing with clients, budgets, deadlines, and ever changing production techniques.
Long-time manager of the UUGDO, Lisa Bartlett, began collecting and scrapbooking samples of the graphic work produced in the University Unions marketing office when she assumed a role there in 1984. When the UUGDO was established in 1985, Bartlett, who was named director, continued this practice. She also maintained a local archive of all digital work files produced by the student designers since the UUGDO's establishment. In addition to her administrative duties in the office, Bartlett supervised and supported student designers and provided supplemental instruction when necessary. In 1985, she was instrumental in the creation of a corporate partnership with Apple, Inc. that has since supplied the technical equipment for the office. In exchange for this support, the UUGDO has produced informational and promotional materials for Apple's national higher education program.
The collection consists of a single series, University Unions Graphic Design Office Student Work, which contains content in hardcopy scrapbooks and digital files maintained online. The collection includes 32 large format scrapbooks and 3.71 GB of digital files. The series presents the graphic design work produced by the office from late 1984 through June 30, 2004.
The scrapbooks contain chronologically arranged samples of final designs. Affixed to the scrapbook pages are the brochures, fliers, logos, signs, and other products created and designed by the UUGDO design staff. For large banners and signs, a photograph of the final product is affixed as an illustration.
The digital files, also arranged chronologically, include source files for final pieces and working drafts, images, and graphics utilized in the production of these designs. The digital works are comprised primarily of raster files in TIFF format, while the remainder are vector files in SVG or PDF formats. Some notable works in the collection include Apple Computers advertisements, Rose Bowl promotional materials, event fliers for campus greek organizations, posters for major campus events, and novelty products. The digital files cover the periods of 1988-1999 and 2004, although future additions of digital material are expected to be made to the collection.
Subjects:
Graphic arts.; Graphic design (Typography); Layout (Printing); Michigan League.; Michigan Union.; Pierpont Commons.; University of Michigan. School of Art & Design.; University of Michigan. University Unions. Graphic Design Office.
Genre Terms:
Scrapbooks.
- Student Graphic Work
  - Scrapbook Volumes circa 1984-2004, 32 volumes
    The scrapbooks contain chronologically arranged samples of final designs. Affixed to the scrapbook pages are the brochures, fliers, logos, signs, and other products created and designed by the UUGDO design staff. For large banners and signs, a photograph of the final product is affixed as an illustration.
    - Pre-December 1984-October 1, 1985 (Volume 1)
    - October 2, 1985-June 26, 1986 (Volume 2)
    - July 1, 1986-December 23, 1986 (Volume 3)
    - January 1, 1987-September 1, 1987 (Volume 4)
    - September 1, 1987-December 23, 1987 (Volume 5)
    - January 1, 1988-May 5, 1988 (Volume 6)
    - May 9, 1988-September 15, 1988 (Volume 7)
    - September 12, 1988-May 4, 1991 (Volume 8)
    - September 15, 1988-January 12, 1989 (Volume 9)
    - January 1, 1989-April 17, 1989 (Volume 10)
    - April 17, 1989-September 21, 1989 (Volume 11)
    - September 22, 1989-October 27, 1989 (Volume 12)
    - October 27, 1989-December 31, 1989 (Volume 13)
    - January 1, 1990-April 6, 1990 (Volume 14)
    - April 1990-September 1990 (Volume 15)
    - September 1990-January 1991 (Volume 16)
    - January 14, 1991-August 27, 1991 (Volume 17)
    - August 7, 1991-March 26, 1992 (Volume 18)
    - March 25, 1992-February 9, 1993 (Volume 19)
    - February 9, 1993-October 14, 1993 (Volume 20)
    - October 15, 1993-April 21, 1994 (Volume 21)
    - April 21, 1994-November 2, 1994 (Volume 22)
    - October 1994-April 18, 1995 (Volume 23)
    - April 1995-November 2, 1995 (Volume 24)
    - December 1995-December 1996 (Volume 25)
    - December 1996-May 1998 (Volume 26)
    - June 1, 1998-May 30, 1999 (Volume 27)
    - June 1, 1999-June 30, 2000 (Volume 28)
    - July 1, 2000-June 30, 2001 (Volume 29)
    - July 1, 2001-June 30, 2002 (Volume 30)
    - July 1, 2002-June 30, 2003 (Volume 31)
    - July 1, 2003-June 30, 2004 (Volume 32)
    - July 1, 2004-June 30, 2006 (Volume 33)
    - July 1, 2006-June 30, 2008 (Volume 34)
    - July 1, 2008-June 30, 2011 (Volume 35)
  - Digital Materials
    The digital files, also arranged chronologically, include source files for final pieces and working drafts, images, and graphics utilized in the production of these designs. The digital works are comprised primarily of raster files in TIFF format, while the remainder are vector files in SVG or PDF formats. Some notable works in the collection include Apple Computers advertisements, Rose Bowl promotional materials, event fliers for campus greek organizations, posters for major campus events, and novelty products. The digital files cover the periods of 1988-1999 and 2004, although future additions of digital material are expected to be made to the collection.
    The digital files are stored in Deep Blue, the University of Michigan's Institutional Repository. Viewing files will require a program to unzip the compressed files and an image viewer/editor to view the graphics files
    - 1987-1988
    - 1989-1990
    - 1990-1991
    - 1991-1992
    - 1992-1993
    - 1993-1994
    - 1994-1995
    - 1995-1996
    - 1996-1997
    - 1997-1998
    - 1998-1999
    - 2003-2004